So we're already meeting to order for March 21st, 2022, Robert Ridal.
I'm going to pray with us and I'm quite pleased with it.
Right.
Got a thank you for this day and I thank you for each person here.
I pray God that you would bless the decisions that are made and bless the people that
make them.
I pray God for this community that we live in that you will have your hand upon it
and the head's around it.
I ask God to be at the people in Ukraine.
That's it to be with our military and our leaders and our president, our country.
It's in your son's name, I pray.
Amen.
A pledge of allegiance to the flag of the United States of America and to the Republic for which
stands one nation under God in the visible with every need of us or all.
Number four, public input and unscheduled personal appearances.
Number five action item, consent agenda, staff is placed on items number six and seven for
our consideration.
Thank you.
Motion wave group.
Second.
Hi.
Don't fall.
December.
Davis.
Hi.
Number eight, action item, work order agreement for inspection services with Anderson Engineering
for 69 a.s.
Surleign as required by the Oklahoma Water Resources Board.
I'd like to see you to 161,000 Mr. Klein.
This is for inspection services for the Secretary of State of New Zealand.
So as part of the loan that we got forward this project, we have to have on five inspectors.
I think it would be better if you have a designer designed the project and that's totally different
engineering for them to watch over the projects.
So that way they're not trying to cover up any mistakes and anything like that they may have had.
So you may have an old-son design the project and then Anderson would review the actual construction
of the bill.
It's a paper work and everything like that.
This is an opportunity to see them out, so hopefully he comes in a little bit now, but we have
to set it up for this.
Thank you.
Motion wave group.
Second.
Exit.
Hi.
December.
Don't fall.
Hi.
Davis.
Thank you.
Number nine, discussion on PCAX charges.
So Council tonight, this agenda item is on here specifically for information and discussion
only.
Tyler has put together a presentation to walk us through the information regarding the
recovery of the utility cost from the 2021 Yeri storm.
And I know we've talked about it quite a bit in the past.
But as we've been going through the last many months putting together options for how we might recover, our cost, the 2.7 million, which we owe to RDA, we've got a lot of options that we've put together here to kind of walk through and start discussing now the ideas, notice no vote tonight, we're going to be just putting it on the board tonight and answering any questions and then a week from now on on the 28th we'll have a work session.
Hopefully by that time it will have given any one in the audience or any citizens that have watched this online and opportunity to do some outreach.
If they have questions to council members and we can then discuss any of that feedback at the work session on the 28th, then again we will come back on the 4th of April.
And at that time we would actually be looking forward if all goes well and opportunity to discuss and vote on an actual solution at that time.
So just wanted to make sure you were aware this is information and we've hopefully baked in a lot of opportunity and time for discussion and input and citizen engagement.
So everybody kind of remembers we talked about this two or three different times but the journey as a little bill was 102 million of that 102 million in the city's portion is about 2.7 million, 2.6 million.
Is that our actual bill, we elected to pay this by October 31st 2022.
So we're going to pay this without paying the carrying costs because if we wanted to pay it over a year to me had to pay interest on it and we didn't want to have interest in carrying costs.
So the ordinance which is also in the packet which is what we would vote online both said the first main April.
But it creates a gerity a rider or PCA so on customer's bills they will have a PCA so if you notice right now you have a PBA purpose fire adjustment on your bill.
I mean a lot of PCA acts on PCA acts and the PCA power costs adjustment acts would be for extreme weather.
So then based on the 2.698 we talked about we have our industrial customers because we did ask them to curtail their load.
So their bill would be a little over a million dollars so we're at, we're going to have them pay us what their actual usage was for that amount of factory.
So you take a million dollars off the 2.7 million in an essence and you have 1.7 million.
So based on the consumption, Jill Calian, all their staff, the help of the time I come up with usage for the other customer classes.
And based on the 1928, 2020, 2021 we have about 170,000 of our PCA acts number which is 0.0 or 0.5 to 2.6.
Which we are going to review that probably every 3 months or so just to make sure that it's coming in as main discipline.
But you know everybody remembers, you know, this normally that was such a large advantage.
That was the ones that have it on the left.
You know, I don't know if everybody remembers the dates, but you know, we had our blackouts, our rolling blackouts
So we had the firm, so on Monday, I remember all I remember forgetting, calling bo and blessing saying hi to you already, saying they might have a blackout on it
So I'm like, you've never done this before
I don't really think we'll get here because we've never done this point, but I was, you know
I was happy I told them because I never thought it would happen
So we had the first one and then the one we had on Tuesday, which was a lot better because we told them hey we have the sophistication
We can just shut stuff down as you need it, so let us pick how we shut it down
So you don't discuss the stuff and everything, we took feeders down to the amount of mango walks they want to down
So it's a lot more, it's a lot better, but you know, it's kind of shows you the advance that went on
Turn that, that weekend February
And just for the
Folks that don't know the
The ups, the upgrades you've done to the substations in recent years
Made that a possibility
I was setting it up to you, we had the lancor, it's up 1 and it's up 3
And they said we need to take on 10 mango walks, so we're looking at each feeder
I think that's 23 February, that last three mango walks, we just shut it down
You know, we sit up, okay, we got, no, we're sticking down until they're happy
And we kind of have a plan that
If it was on off on it, then the hour, then we're going to rotate it
We do different feeders, so those people can warm their houses back up
Because I mean it was extremely cold then, and then take other people off
We don't want to take the hospital off
Some places like that, some critical things
So, I'm very happy that we have the technology to do that
There are some cities that don't have their whole town
We've locked up because they don't have to stay over there
There, there were other communities, other GRDA customers
But we're just at the mercy of the lack of
Unlike where my amount was able to at least apply some logic
To the lack of out and be more strategic with it
So that we impacted fewer people for fewer people
And that was some great part of his crew did an amazing job
Made it in that, in a very critical crisis
I didn't hear any criticism, they're not that far over by the audio
I have to go someday, I want to bring our state and to show you the real time of it now
And I got that in my dinner table now, and it's set down, take down on feeders and stuff
So I got to see it, it was really cool
This kit is going to show us the available generation and SPP market
So GRDA gets their power, the generic power with this, we get it all
SPP, this office power pool, there are a number of this shows you
Why was there built so high?
Well, February 8th, I think they were fine after we asked for two or three dollars
In the back of the earth, and then look, if everyone jumps up, it's going to 200, 400
And then what February 18th, it's over a thousand dollars a decade later
I'm going to ask where the huge cost came in
So as GRDA obviously has multiple sources of fuel that they...
used to generate electricity, the high-growth coal, and at her gas when, obviously, the natural
gas is what had the greatest impact on the cost to generate the storm.
And so, as Tyler is explaining, GRDA is when he says, then, GRDA is who he's talking
about, had to go buy it off from the open market and pay open market prices, and so that's
what caused these just catastrophic costs to generate over 40 pounds.
So, I'll talk about, so, the day-hand in 2020, it was $17.6 and $0.6 and $0.6 and $0.6 and
it took a mega lot, and there was times, you know, it got $24,000 a mega lot, so, you know,
you're about to place this in Texas that they had, you can have whoever, supplier, and you
want, you can pay for what you pay daily, so, you know, some people used to make a lot of $4,000
so they got their bill and, exactly, high-opening, you know, instead of having a set rate, like,
the...
This is kind of shows they're monthly, you know, they're generation, the PCX, when we talk about,
in your pocket, it talks about different the breakdown, and the next slide, but our average,
based on our last-rate study, the average residential customer uses about $900 KW to month, and
it just kind of shows you the breakdown, so our PCX now, you set the point, $0.05, $2.26, so,
like I said, we'll review and update this because it's going to change on usage, but if you take
that time, if your home use is out, then KW to month, maybe about $5.25, $5.26, use $1500, be that, I mean,
and...
So, that, that basically gives you an idea of how the city will recover the $1.7 million remaining
after the industrial folks, check in their portion, the residential is the $1.7 that's left,
but the idea was we would spread this out to minimize as much of the impact on our residential
customers as possible, and so that's what this option, that we're talking to the Council
about nine when we talk about it over the next several weeks is, you know, as our average
customers around the 1,000 KWH, they would see a $5.22 average PCX charge on their monthly
bill.
And if we do that per 1,000 kilowatt, for our residential customers over several years, we should
be able to recoup that with minimal impact, but we realize that every dollar counts, so this
has been something that we have talked about.
for months. We have agonized over, we have talked with council members, we've talked in a executive session, we've
re-end different scenarios, because we know that our residents, every dollar matters, and we don't want it to come
down to one of our residents having to decide if they go pick up their medicine this month or they pay their
electric bill. And so we wanted to do this in a way that we could stretch out where it was
physically responsible for the city. We stretched out too far, we're going to do locating efforts in
the future of a certain potential impact of a storm or something that could happen in the future that
could impact here. So we had to be responsible and put it a reasonable time frame, but keep the
cost low enough that we thought the customers could absorb the cost. It just did not go without
great effort in consideration for our folks, which is why we're here. It's a survey.
For example, is this a sliding scale? For example, if you are somewhere between 1,000 and 1,500
are you paying 5,000 to 6,000 or if you're 12,000 to 15,000. So you just do just say what you're using.
Just talked about that. She has a bill that on her next presentation, we can actually put
that explanation on the side. So it would be like a sliding scale? Well, whatever, whatever,
you used it to be, it was multiplied by 0,500. Okay. I got you. And like I said, this number will
change based on usage. I mean, hopefully everything comes in. I hope like the numbers we've
received that will project it and it comes in like participating in. Maybe even less than
the number, but maybe it doesn't come in. Because people may be conserving their electric because they
are watching for this, so we have to, you know, raise it up next slide. The hope is that they had often
three years based on the 0,500 or 0,500. And like those that we look at many different ways, I mean,
kind of like some other things I've talked to you, they've had a straight feet and, you know,
the same as a doctor. And then there's a manual way, it's kind of the most fair because people can actually
watch their meal and to be cognizant of their usage. You can see the X number, so you can just
share and speak in here. And I've talked about the dates. So kind of the plan is, you know,
discussed tonight at Council of Attitude, and I go or receive any questions. I'm going to give you
another answers and bring them back to the next meeting. But you have any, you know, if you guys
come up with any questions, then I'd love to bring the word next.
Thank you, Tyler.
Number 10, other new business, if any, which is a reason, since the post you know it's
agenda, staff reports are in the packet, trustee and community announcements.
The adjournment.
So, let's say it.
Go for it.